<recipe id="4" lang="en" title="knau" spiciness="3" week="23" year="2012" preparationtime="10" cooktime="15" image="http://www.weeklythairecipe.com/public/images/NewRecipe.jpg" fornumberofpersons="3">
  <ingredients>
    <item>100 grams chickenfilet or breast</item>
    <item>1 cup of chicken stock/bouillon</item>
    <item>1 cup of coconutmilk</item>
    <item>3 pieces fresh or frozen lemongrass</item>
    <item>2 kaffir limeleaves torn</item>
    <item>6 slices of galangal(ginger)</item>
    <item>2 or 3 red chillies in big slices diagonally</item>
    <item>2 tablespoons of lime juice</item>
    <item>1 tablespoon fish sauce,better called nam pla</item>
    <item>½ tablespoon palmsugar</item>
    <item>2 tablespoons pak chee(coriander)</item>
    <item>4 big straw mushrooms or regular mushrooms sliced</item>
    <item>3 little tomatos</item>
  </ingredients>
  <directions>
    <paragraph>First we prepare the lemongrass, use only the bottom white part (about 6 inches),cut off the woody grass part of it. With the flat side of a knife or a heavy object, crush the lemongrass so the flavour comes free. Cut into 2 inch skices.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Put the chickenstock into a pot and bring it to boil. Then put in the galangal, lemongrass, sugar and lime leaves. Let it boil on a low heat for 5 minutes. Add the coconut milk, chillies, fish sauce and boil on a low heat for another 5 minutes.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Then add the chicken tomatos and mushrooms and cook till the chicken is just cooked. When the chicken is all white on the outside, it's 90% done. Turn off the heat, add the lime juice and garnish with the pak chee leaves.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Taste your soup, it must be a little bit salty, but most of all sweet and sour. Sweet from the coconut milk and sour from the limejuice. Than again spicy from the chillies. If needed you can bring your soup at taste wit nam pla(salt), lemon juice (sour), coconutmilk and sugar(sweet).</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Be sure you add the lemonjuice at the end otherwise it looses its fresh taste.</paragraph>
  </directions>
</recipe>